<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aleksandr Petrosyan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aleksandr Petrosyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mental Hygiene</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writers-block-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writers-block-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this at a very awkward moment in my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the one hand a great many things have tuned out better than one could have hoped.  I have a stable job, where I got promoted quite recently.  I do stuff that is quite interesting, and I learn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the last few weeks have been harrowing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of friends, people that would normally be well-off in deep trouble.  While I stand by that AI will not affect one&amp;rsquo;s ability to feed themselves (at least not negatively), other &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; intelligence do their best to do so.  I have a brilliant Hungarian that is deeply depressed.  I can act as if it&amp;rsquo;s easy to fix, but it is not.  I barely manage to hide the symptoms most of the time, much less know of a cure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Emacs widget toolkit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-widget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I outline the consequences of several months worth of deliberation and dumpster diving into the Emacs display code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article I shall outline the potential direction in which to take the Emacs widget toolkit, a plan to revitalise Emacs and get it to a state that would allow newcomers to appreciate it for the marvel of engineering that it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But first let&amp;rsquo;s talk about problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semver is a mixed bag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/semver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/semver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in a bit of a pickle.  I like rust quite a bit, but I find myself having to solve one recurring problem over and over.  The dreaded &lt;code&gt;zeroize&lt;/code&gt; issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some background I work in blockchains.  That means cryptography.  That means dealing with a mixture of grade level mathematics masquerading as something profound; script kiddies putting you &amp;ldquo;in your place&amp;rdquo; if you disagree with the holy scripture, libraries that have seen better days, that you are not allowed to modify, and a tar-like resistance to treating security as a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs lisp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/emacs-lisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/emacs-lisp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post dedicated to the configuration language of my favourite editor: Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is true that Emacs owes its flexibility and very configurable nature  to this wonderful and awful language.  It is both its greatest strength and weakness.  It is simply the brick wall that is responsible for the learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is also the major source of the reasons why Emacs can&amp;rsquo;t be made either asynchronous or multi-threaded.  Or at least, not in the usual sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Of Blockchains and Banks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blockchain-vs-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blockchain-vs-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Preface&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#preface&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting discussion with many people that have in one way or another echoed the point of view that cryptocurrencies in general are a blight on society.  While a wiser man than I cautioned against accepting the premise of the bully, in this case doing so is instrumental in dismantling the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Participation in the cryptocurrencies is voluntary.  As any emerging technology it had some rough edges, and when compared to the recurring economical fiascos of the traditional banking system, blockchains have demonstrated a profound improvement in some areas, and problematic behaviours in others were not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Stallmangate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/stallmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/stallmann/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the unofficial name that was given to the controversy that involved a blatant violation of the GitHub terms of service, and instigated a personal attack on the founder of Free Software Foundation, Richard Matthew Stallamann.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not here to either defend or explain my choice to not participate in the &amp;ldquo;sign or be unhirable in Open Source&amp;rdquo; open letter, and my decision to  side with the countervailing party.  I will merely mention that it was a decision to choose the lesser of two evils, and that this is what has transpired as a result.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language servers in Emacs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-lsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-lsp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will try to summarise my experience with all things LSP (language server protocol).  I will talk primarily about the two most important implementations of LSP for Emacs: &lt;code&gt;eglot&lt;/code&gt; that is built into Emacs, and &lt;code&gt;lsp-mode&lt;/code&gt; that seems to be much more feature complete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will delve into the pros and cons of both, explain why I use both as daily drivers and why I prefer to not have them be enabled by default for any mode, and what to do if you don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of LSP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting comfortable with rejection and failure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a rather long-winded piece of wisdom that I have picked up from multiple sources.  It is meant largely for a few people in my immediate audience, whom I know and love and have every intention of helping along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have not learned this overnight.  &lt;em&gt;Errare humanum est&lt;/em&gt;.  While I do not presume to know more than the other person, there are some strategies that I have found to be useful.  This article lists but a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set up LSP in Emacs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lsp-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lsp-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a semi-rant, but I believe a worthwhile use of my time.  There&#xA;are two compliant implementations of the language server protocol,&#xA;which do not have a bipartisan objective review attached to them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some would argue that &lt;code&gt;eglot&lt;/code&gt; is superior by virtue of being in the&#xA;Emacs core, some would instead argue that &lt;code&gt;lsp-mode&lt;/code&gt; is more feature&#xA;complete and far more lenient towards language servers with&#xA;non-standard extensions.  Those are true, but they only affect the&#xA;first-hand experience, something that only a total script kiddie will&#xA;complain about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping your emacs speedy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-quick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-quick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;keeping-your-emacs-speedy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Keeping your emacs speedy&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#keeping-your-emacs-speedy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a topic that came up because of three things.  The two Emacs blogs that came up on the Planet Emacs RSS feed talked about retaining a minimal configuration and keeping it minimal, providing good advice.  I don&amp;rsquo;t wish to dismantle those blog entries, but merely point out that minimalism can be useful for things other than aesthetic minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to learn to program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-programmers-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/young-programmers-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-learn-to-program&#34;&gt;&#xA;  How to learn to program&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#how-to-learn-to-program&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;::: tip&#xA;A much more detailed guide is going to be published on the Greybeard&#xA;blog.  So stay tuned.&#xA;:::&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of a short guide, and it&amp;rsquo;s required to be short for one simple reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of advice there on the internet.  A lot of it is correct, but it&#xA;comes with an implicit contextual limitation.  The people like Uncle Bob&#xA;Martin, Johnathan Blow, and perhaps Casey Muratori, are all referring to&#xA;programmers that have intrinsically different levels of experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declarative configuration in Emacs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-use-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-use-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;declarative-configuration-in-emacs&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Declarative configuration in Emacs&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#declarative-configuration-in-emacs&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Emacs, it is often easiest to install a package in one&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;initialising configuration file; also known as &lt;code&gt;init.el&lt;/code&gt;, usually&#xA;located at &lt;code&gt;~/config/emacs/init.el&lt;/code&gt;, but also historically at&#xA;&lt;code&gt;~/.emacs.d/init.el&lt;/code&gt; as under a different name &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This file is responsible for reading your persistent configuration and&#xA;is often written to by your resident Emacs binary, on first launch and&#xA;after you&amp;rsquo;ve made some customisations.  It is configured in Lisp,&#xA;which is both a data representation format (Symbolic expressions), and&#xA;a programming language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs in 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-keybinds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-keybinds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;emacs-in-2024&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Emacs in 2024&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#emacs-in-2024&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a major user of Emacs.  But I&amp;rsquo;m not, for lack of a better term, an&#xA;Emacs zealot.  If you ask me what editor should you use, the answer&#xA;isn&amp;rsquo;t automatically, or often, Emacs.  The zealots believe that it is&#xA;enough to cite the power, and the relatively low skill floor for Emacs&#xA;to be an optimal choice, but I would say that I disagree vehemently.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve even written about it (hint: look in the &lt;strong&gt;rants&lt;/strong&gt; section).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A zeroth-order guide to privelege escalation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/privilege-escalation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/privilege-escalation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not meant to be a detailed comparison, just a&#xA;back-of-the-envelope guide explaining why you should or shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use&#xA;a particular program in particular circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sudo&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#sudo&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is sadly, considered the default on most GNU+Linux&#xA;distributions.  It is a rather complex beast, despite the fact that it&#xA;is, for lack of a better term, the original &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt;, an ugly piece&#xA;of code that almost everyone hates, but still runs for some reason.&#xA;Not to say that &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; is bad, these days it&amp;rsquo;s perhaps what it was&#xA;meant to be all along, but &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; is something that you likely need to&#xA;know about, but also something that you should avoid if possible on&#xA;your own machines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writers block and how to deal with it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writers-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writers-block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;writers-block-and-how-to-deal-with-it&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Writers block and how to deal with it&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#writers-block-and-how-to-deal-with-it&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s rough analogue is brain constipation.  It causes you to have either too many or too few thoughts; the one that occurred to me, resulted in around 15 articles half-started, going in a direction which made me rather uncomfortable publishing.  Consequently, despite having written a significant amount, I&amp;rsquo;ve not published much.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So how do you deal with this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remasters should not exist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/remasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/remasters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a very controversial topic and perhaps one that will land me a lot of enemies.  I nonetheless believe that it is imperative to understand the point: the existence of game remasters is a symptom of a larger problem, that will soon become all-encompassing.  It is my firm belief that we as a species have blundered our way to this problem unknowingly, and that we can still fix it&amp;hellip; albeit with a lot of effort, specifically pertaining to unlearning some of the bad habits that we have accumulated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A case against &#34;Cat-v considered harmful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/cat-v-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/cat-v-harmful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-case-against-cat-v-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;&#xA;  A case against &amp;ldquo;Cat-v considered harmful&amp;rdquo;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#a-case-against-cat-v-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a rant that&amp;rsquo;s a long time coming, and it is a lukewarm shot at a community that I have a love-hate relationship with.  Sure, &lt;code&gt;cat-v&lt;/code&gt; and by extension the good-old-unix hacker groups are quite interesting, and quite enticing to join, but I&amp;rsquo;m a little concerned with people who might take it more seriously than that deserves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language elitism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/language_elitism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/language_elitism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: info&#xA;I must preface this by pointing to something that should be blindingly obvious, but shall be taken out of context regardless.  This is not a personal attack on Drew De Vault.  While one might construe our relationship as antagonistic I have respect for a lot of what he is doing.  We are of differing and in some ways incompatible political views, and have different approaches to programming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the very object of the following text is to mock antagonism with such flimsy footing.  The subject of the mockery is language elitism, conveyed through the lens of a frustrated rant by Drew De Vault, and demonstrated as a deconstruction of the &amp;ldquo;destruction&amp;rdquo;.  I will posit that all attempts to espouse such an opinion for any reason is fundamentally misguided.&#xA;:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Neovim challenge, one month later</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/neovim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is quite an interesting experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will not say that I am wholly disappointed, but that it is sad. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a &lt;code&gt;vi&lt;/code&gt; user for the better part of my teens, and I&amp;rsquo;ve only picked up Emacs around ten years ago, when I was 19. So this challenge was less of a dive into foreign waters, and more of a return to my own roots. And it is interesting to see your grandparents do some renovations, to see signs of prosperity in some areas, but to also notice that they are struggling. Not financially, but in that they&amp;rsquo;ve lost track of what made them who they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set up Magit forge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/magit-forge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/magit-forge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-set-up-magit-forge&#34;&gt;&#xA;  How to set up Magit forge&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#how-to-set-up-magit-forge&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magit is an excellent package with incredible depth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sadly it is accompanied by the most unreadable documentation which is saying something, given that it&amp;rsquo;s an Emacs package.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here I will detail an example configuration to set up a GitHub to magit interface.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;github&#34;&gt;&#xA;  GitHub&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#github&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the default, and probably most relevant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set up KeepassXC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/keepassxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/keepassxc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SSH has some of the dumbest ideas in UX.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rather than use the fact that the person responsible for the creation of this program is capable of such stupidity so as to discredit ssh, we politely forgive them for flaunting &amp;ldquo;I am a security expert&amp;rdquo; as if that makes their stupidity &lt;em&gt;more forgivable&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enough ranting though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re here to set up KeePassXC on a clean Arch installation as an SSH agent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown considered harmful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had complaints about Markdown for years. I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. Is it better than e.g. writing your code in ReST, I&amp;rsquo;d argue marginally, and only if you assume that ReST was meant to be used in the same circumstances as Markdown, which it does not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, if your life revolves around Markdown, this article will make your life a bit easier, not by a lot, but still. I&amp;rsquo;d make the case that we&amp;rsquo;re better off leaving Markdown behind, and instead to move beyond &amp;ldquo;lightweight&amp;rdquo; text-based markup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs, the editor for the ages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post dedicated to my, and many other people&amp;rsquo;s favourite text editor. In-keeping with the theme of this section, I shall mainly focus on the misunderstood nature of the editor, and my personal connection to it. Most of it is going to be in the negative light, so it slightly edges out being posted in the Software section.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without further ado.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;&#xA;  About me&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#about-me&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I feel like a hostage.&#xA;This is not something that I can &amp;hellip; for lack of a better word admit to lightly.&#xA;Emacs is a tool that I&amp;rsquo;ve invested into heavily.&#xA;The problem is however that I have some long-standing pain points that I hope can someday be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I don&#39;t like about Vitepress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/vitepress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/vitepress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a continuation of the rant about static site generation systems. While I liked vitepress a lot more than I like Jekyll I still have some issues with how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In principle it is one of the better static site generators in my opinion, probably better than anything that I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with so far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it begs the question of &amp;ldquo;does a static site generator as a concept&amp;rdquo; need to exist?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I don&#39;t like about Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps a fitting beginning to the first blog post on my home page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I FUCKING HATE JEKYLL.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite surprised, and frankly appalled at the fact that there are few if any useful tools for generating static sites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started off with Jekyll, because it seemed like the right tool for the job, after all it is supported by GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, frankly, proudly hosted by the same people that brought to you Atom, then Atom EEE edition, then managed to move what was perfectly logical and could be done via a regular UI with convenient previews into &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;, seems like a fitting endorsement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
