<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markup Languages on Aleksandr Petrosyan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/markup-languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markup Languages on Aleksandr Petrosyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/markup-languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Markdown considered harmful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had complaints about Markdown for years. I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. Is it better than e.g. writing your code in ReST, I&amp;rsquo;d argue marginally, and only if you assume that ReST was meant to be used in the same circumstances as Markdown, which it does not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, if your life revolves around Markdown, this article will make your life a bit easier, not by a lot, but still. I&amp;rsquo;d make the case that we&amp;rsquo;re better off leaving Markdown behind, and instead to move beyond &amp;ldquo;lightweight&amp;rdquo; text-based markup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I don&#39;t like about Vitepress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/vitepress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/vitepress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a continuation of the rant about static site generation systems. While I liked vitepress a lot more than I like Jekyll I still have some issues with how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In principle it is one of the better static site generators in my opinion, probably better than anything that I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with so far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it begs the question of &amp;ldquo;does a static site generator as a concept&amp;rdquo; need to exist?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I don&#39;t like about Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rants/jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps a fitting beginning to the first blog post on my home page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I FUCKING HATE JEKYLL.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite surprised, and frankly appalled at the fact that there are few if any useful tools for generating static sites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started off with Jekyll, because it seemed like the right tool for the job, after all it is supported by GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, frankly, proudly hosted by the same people that brought to you Atom, then Atom EEE edition, then managed to move what was perfectly logical and could be done via a regular UI with convenient previews into &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;, seems like a fitting endorsement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
